# Noah Husain

## Software Developer

+1916-599-3361

noahhusain@gmail.com

github.com/NoahHusain

<u>linkedin.com/in/noah-husain</u>

### About

Before starting my journey in software development, I was working as a Front Office Lead at one of California's largest pediatric dental chains with a focus on serving under-represented communities. At the onset of the pandemic, I lost my job and decided to pivot my career towards software development. I began with Python and got the fundamentals down quickly before then continuing onto JavaScript where I made some lighting profiles for RGB keyboards while learning the language. Feeling that I was hitting the limit on what I could teach myself, I joined Nashville Software School to continue increasing my knowledge of software development. I'm excited to join the Nashville Tech Community!

#### **Projects**

# Truncheons & Flagons | Group Project | <u>View Code</u> Tech Stack: HTLM5, CSS, JavaScript, JSON

Truncheons Flagons is a companion app for the medieval drinking game similar to beer pong. The app tracks tracks teams, users, and scores to make your games as streamlined as possible. I handled the scoring component of the application including monitoring scores in between rounds, displaying current score, and tallying of final scores.

# Mines-R-Us | Capstone Project | <u>View Code</u> Tech Stack: HTLM5, CSS, JavaScript, React, JSON

Mines-R-Us is a companion app made for miners in the game "Star Citizen". Designed to be the one stop shop for miners in the game, it shows all relevant info miners need to be as profitable as possible such as ore patch locations, ore prices, equipment costs, and a beginners guide for those getting into the game. All aspects of the application were built by me. This includes the JSON database, React modules, and CSS styling.

#### **Tech Skills**

- JavaScript, React, Python, SQL, Django, HTML, CSS
- · Excellent Interpersonal Skills
- · Problem Solving Skills
- · Ability to learn new systems
- · Desire to learn

#### **Technical Experience**

#### **Nashville Software School**

Software Developer 2021-2021

Intensive full-time 6-month software development bootcamp anchoring learning with both individual and team-based projects. Tech Stack: Python/Django; React.js; JavaScript; HTML5; CSS3; SQL fundamentals.

- Single-page applications utilizing React, HTML, and JavaScript.
- GitHub to perform and review pull requests to ensure code is safe to merge with no conflicts.
- Introduced to the Agile environment by frequent collaborative projects using tickets, pull requests, stand ups, and code reviews.
- Taught fundamentals of code such as HTML, CSS,
   JSON, modular code, reusable components, as well as using Entity Relationship Diagrams for databases.

### Professional Experience

#### **Front Office Lead**

Children Choice Pediatric Dental Care 2019-2020

- · General Office Duties
- · Auditing of patient charts prior and after appointments
- Training of new staff on front office duties and Standard Operating Procedures
- · Managing front and back office of the clinic
- · Receiving inbound phone calls from patients
- Making outbound phone calls to patient to schedule appointments
- Monitoring of Google, Yelp, and Facebook reviews and calling patients to discuss their visits and what we can improve on when negative reviews were left
- Monitoring of new patient number metrics and coordinating with marketing on where we can market our office to boost our numbers
- Ensuring all needs of the back office are supplied when under heavy patient loads (instruments, sterilization of tools, cleaning chairs, seating patients)

#### **Marketing Assistant**

Children Choice Pediatric Dental Care 2016-2019

- · Develop and generate marketing reports, sponsorships, event planning, customer relations, and giveaways
- · General Office Duties
- Develop and execute processes with each marketing campaign
- · Attending sponsored events to foster brand image with the community
- Performed informational oral health care demonstrations for schools within the community
- Develop and provide reports on negative review reconciliation with patients
- Outbound call generation to general practitioners, schools, and parents
- Implemented various marketing programs to boost referrals to our practice
- Analysis of marketing reports by preparing full statistics report on new patient numbers via referrals from General Practitioners, Google, Facebook, and outreach programs

#### Education

#### **Nashville Software School**

Full-time Web Development Bootcamp

### **Grand Canyon University**

Business Administration 90 Semester Units Completed